[
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, what is the view from Dr. Haber's window in the Oregon Oneirological Institute?",
        "a": "a mountain range",
        "b": "a beach with ocean",
        "c": "a city skyline",
        "d": "a desert landscape",
        "e": "a primeval forest",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, what Dr. Haber regards his work with?",
        "a": "frustration",
        "b": "enthusiasm",
        "c": "indifference",
        "d": "satisfaction",
        "e": "resentment",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, why does Haber say that he keeps one patient of his own?",
        "a": "to have a source of income",
        "b": "to have an experimental subject",
        "c": "to have someone to talk to",
        "d": "to keep his private practice going",
        "e": "to keep his work grounded",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Dr. Haber, what is morality?",
        "a": "the pursuit of study and research",
        "b": "the good one does to others",
        "c": "the extent of one's influence over other people",
        "d": "the expression of individual will",
        "e": "the practice of organized religion",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of animals did Haber use in his early experiments?",
        "a": "birds",
        "b": "fish",
        "c": "rats",
        "d": "dogs",
        "e": "cats",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, how does Dr. Haber say that the Augmentor saves time?",
        "a": "by inducing specific stages of sleep in the subject",
        "b": "by manipulating dream content and emotional affect",
        "c": "by reinforcing the subject's own typical d-state activity",
        "d": "by inducing alpha waves in the brain",
        "e": "by conditioning patients to dream safely",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, what metaphor does Orr to describe his feeling of being crowded and squeezed?",
        "a": "Overstimulation",
        "b": "Fear of being touched",
        "c": "Anxiety",
        "d": "Fear of confinement",
        "e": "Overpopulation",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, what is the significance of Orr’s eyes moving under his eyelids?",
        "a": "It shows that Orr is having an effective dream.",
        "b": "It suggests that Orr is waking up.",
        "c": "It is a sign of muscle tension in Orr.",
        "d": "It indicates that Orr is experiencing REM sleep.",
        "e": "It signals the onset of Orr’s deep fourth-stage sleep",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, what does the high-voltage peak in the EEG trace indicate?",
        "a": "a highly emotional dream-experience",
        "b": "the onset of deep sleep",
        "c": "creative or artistic brain activity",
        "d": "a malfunction of the Augmentor",
        "e": "the onset of rapid eye movement (REM) sleep",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, how does Miss Lelache react to seeing the effects of George’s dream at the Oregon Oneirological institute?",
        "a": "with shock and disbelief",
        "b": "with fear and terror",
        "c": "with excitement and interest",
        "d": "with awe and wonder",
        "e": "with greed and eagerness",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Haber's opinion on the state of Oregon after Orr’s effective dream in Chapter Five?",
        "a": "It is the most unspoiled state in the country",
        "b": "It is the most overpopulated state in the country",
        "c": "It is a state with a lot of potential for economic growth",
        "d": "It is a state with vast environmental and physical resources.",
        "e": "It is the most polluted state in the country",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, what does Miss Lelache ask herself after she sees Orr’s effective dream?",
        "a": "if she is in Hell",
        "b": "if she is dreaming",
        "c": "if she is drunk",
        "d": "if she is in love with Orr",
        "e": "if she is having a crazy spell",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter Five, what is the subject of Orr’s dream about overpopulation?",
        "a": "a fire",
        "b": "a plague",
        "c": "an earthquake",
        "d": "a flood",
        "e": "a war",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a feature of the new, no longer overpopulated world that Orr dreams into existence in Chapter 5?",
        "a": "flowering of creativity",
        "b": "freedom of speech and thought",
        "c": "sufficient food for all",
        "d": "a universal skin color",
        "e": "respect for nature",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "With what toast does Dr. Haber end Chapter Five?",
        "a": "“To new beginnings!”",
        "b": "“To love and friendship!”",
        "c": "“To absent friends!”",
        "d": "“To good health!”",
        "e": "“To a better world!”",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter 6, George thinks of himself as a(n)",
        "a": "alien",
        "b": "leader",
        "c": "patsy",
        "d": "seeker",
        "e": "tool",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter 6, George thinks that his dreams could be useful if they",
        "a": "change the world",
        "b": "win Heather Lelache’s love",
        "c": "improve his life",
        "d": "aid scientific research",
        "e": "make him rich and famous",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who telephones George Orr in Chapter 6?",
        "a": "Orr’s boss",
        "b": "Mannie",
        "c": "Dr. Haber",
        "d": "Heather Lelache",
        "e": "Orr’s mother",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does Miss Lelache feel about the Augmentor in Chapter 6?",
        "a": "enthusiastic",
        "b": "indifferent",
        "c": "skeptical",
        "d": "curious",
        "e": "fearful",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does Orr realize about his job when talking to Heather Lelache?",
        "a": "He works for a private tools firm in French Glen.",
        "b": "He is a draftsman for the District.",
        "c": "He works for Bradford Industries downtown.",
        "d": "He is unemployed.",
        "e": "He works for the Bonneville-Umatilla water projects.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does Orr see in the living room of his new apartment in depopulated Portland?",
        "a": "a woodframe fireplace",
        "b": "a modern glass table",
        "c": "a velvet sofa",
        "d": "a Persian carpet",
        "e": "a grand piano",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the phenothiazines that Haber gives George Orr in Chapter 6?",
        "a": "to induce hallucinations",
        "b": "to make his dreams more effective",
        "c": "to treat a nervous tremor",
        "d": "to prevent him from dreaming altogether",
        "e": "to weaken the intensity of his dreams",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter 6, what is the current situation in Saudi Arabia and Iraq?",
        "a": "The area has been abandoned and left uninhabited.",
        "b": "The civilian population lives in underground burrows.",
        "c": "There is no government or law and order.",
        "d": "The population is thriving and prosperous.",
        "e": "The area is a tourist destination.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter 6, what does George Orr say when Haber asks him about the purpose of life?",
        "a": "The goal of life is to achieve a better world.",
        "b": "Not everything has to have a purpose.",
        "c": "Meaning is self-created.",
        "d": "We must live in harmony with nature.",
        "e": "The environment matters more than people.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter 6, Dr. Haber asks George if he has ever studied",
        "a": "Greek philosophy",
        "b": "quantum physics",
        "c": "higher mathematics",
        "d": "Eastern mysticism",
        "e": "natural science",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter 6, Dr. Haber tells George to dream about",
        "a": "interspecies communication",
        "b": "universal peace",
        "c": "space travel",
        "d": "wealth and fame",
        "e": "climate rejuvenation",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which new word does George Orr find himself using after one of his dreams in Chapter 6?",
        "a": "cislunar",
        "b": "interspeciesence",
        "c": "exopulse",
        "d": "cosmotide",
        "e": "galaxysm",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why does Dr. Haber give George Orr sodium pentothal in Chapter 6?",
        "a": "to make him speak the truth",
        "b": "to cure him",
        "c": "to cause him pain",
        "d": "to suppress his dreams",
        "e": "to induce hypnosis",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chapter 6, Dr. Haber says that the unconscious mind is a",
        "a": "groundless set of assumptions",
        "b": "useful framework for psychotherapy",
        "c": "wellspring of heath",
        "d": "source of creativity and imagination",
        "e": "black pit of nightmares",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "When Orr worries about his lack of control over his dreams in Chapter 6, Haber says that he is",
        "a": "going to stop dreaming soon",
        "b": "acting in a civilized way",
        "c": "full of groundless fears",
        "d": "already gaining more control",
        "e": "working toward freedom",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    }
]

